Guide to the Turkish Photography Collection 1910-1990 AD.MC.007
AbuDhabi
Turkey Collection
Bulk, 1940-1950
1910-1990
AD.MC.007
AbuDhabi
10.0 Paige boxes 10000 photos
Box 1-10
Biographical/Historical note
Akkasah, the Center for Photography at NYU Abu Dhabi, explores the histories and contemporary practices of photography in the Arab world from comparative perspectives: it fosters the scholarly study of these histories and practices in dialogue with other photographic cultures and traditions from around the world. Through a range of activities, the center also supports the developing photographic culture in the UAE. Akkasah aims to contribute to the crossroad encounters of Arabian Peninsula, through an ongoing program of conferences, colloquia, publications, workshops, artist residencies, and exhibitions and through the creation of a photographic archive.
Arrangement note
This collection was processed as it was acquired.
Conditions Governing Access note
Digitization of this collection is underway; thumbnail images will be published here as they become available.
Custodial History note
The collection was acquired through various dealers and private collectors in Turkey.
Scope and Contents note
Akkasah’s collection from Turkey currently includes more than 15,000 images from the late Ottoman era and the modern Turkish Republic. The collection is comprised primarily of amateur photographs from family albums and of individual and group portraits taken in various studios across Turkey. Though many date back to the first decade of the 20th century and some are from as late as the 1970s and 1980s, the core of the collection focuses on the period from the 1920s through to the end of the 1950s. The collection also contains a substantial number of orientalist postcards from major Ottoman cities including Istanbul, Cairo, Alexandria, Port Said, Damascus and Beirut.
- Two women, one in traditional clothes. Foto Saray. 20.5 x 14.9 cm, Undated; Unkown, Mr/Ms (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Fashion Accessories; Foto Saray; Furnishings; Istanbul, Turkey; Jewelry; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Traditional Dress; Women
- Two covered women in black with a little girl standing on a chair. Ottoman and Turkish writing on the reverse. 16.4 x 13.9 cm, 17 August 1926; Unkown, Mr/Ms (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Children; Furnishings; Head Covers; Ottoman Writing; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Turkish Writing; Women
- A large multi-generational family group, an older couple is seated in the middle. Studio stamp on the back. 19.4 x 24.9 cm, Undated; Unkown, Mr/Ms (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Children; Coats; Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Family Portraits; Head Covers; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey
- Darulfunun Geography Class (Istanbul University today). Names in Ottoman writing on the reverse. 29.7 x 23.7 cm, 1919; Unkown, Mr/Ms (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Education; Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Fez; Istanbul, Turkey; Maps; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; University
- Man in a suit and fez, with a handlebar mustache. 28.5 x 20.3 cm, Undated; Unkown, Mr/Ms (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Fez; Furnishings; Mustaches; Ottoman Writing; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits; Turkey
- A young woman with a long necklace wearing a long skirt, holding a clutch, in a garden. 28.5 x 18.7 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Fashion Accessories; Gardens; Individual Portrait; Jewelry; Photographic Prints; Trees; Turkey; Women
- Small family group, male is wearing a kalpak. 23.2 x 16.4 cm, 19 [-?-] 1929 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Children; Coats; Family; Family Portraits; Hats; Ottoman Writing; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey
- An Armenian family, an older couple are seated in the middle. Armenian writing on the back. 21.7 x 28.2 cm, Undated; Unkown, Mr/Ms (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Armenian Writing; Family Portraits; Fez; Jewelry; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits; Turkey
- Military officer in uniform. Foto H. Anil, Gelibolu, Turkey. Turkish writing on the back. 29.7 x 19.0 cm, 26 October 1942; Unkown, Mr/Ms (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Gelibolu, Turkey; Individual Portrait; Military; Mustaches; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkish Writing; Uniforms
- Primary school class photo outside a building. Turkish writing on the back. 21.0 x 26.3 cm, 1966 - 1967 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Children; Education; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Schools; Turkey; Turkish Writing
- Military officer, sitting with a cane. Foto Fazil, Manisa, Turkey. 28.0 x 21.9 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Furnishings; Individual Portrait; Manisa, Turkey; Military; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Uniforms
- A collage of different photographs, "Keguyiagopyan" written on the back. 29.5 x 18.5 cm, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Family; Military; Photographic Prints; Smoking; Soldiers; Turkey; Turkish Writing; Uniforms
- A soldier with glasses, looking off camera. 27.7 x 20.0 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Individual Portrait; Military; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Uniforms
- A woman and a small child sitting on a bench. 20.4 x 16.6 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Children; Family Portraits; Furnishings; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Women
- A group at a dinner table. Names of the guests on the front. Foto Beyaz Saray, Istanbul, Turkey. 19.5 x 23.8 cm, 26 November 1952 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Alcohol; Drinking; Eating; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Photographic Prints; Restaurants; Studio Photography
- A man with short mustache - Phebus, Constantinople. 19.9 x 28.2 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Constantinople; Individual Portrait; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Mustaches; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
- A family group, man with a white scarf around his neck, girls in patterned dresses. 19.2 x 25.2 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Children; Family; Gardens; Photographic Prints; Turkey
- A small family group, a young girl with a sailor's hat sits in the middle. 21.5 x 15.4 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Family; Family Portraits; Hats; Head Covers; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Women
- A group of men sitting at table, eating. 18.2 x 24.4 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Drinking; Eating; Gatherings; Men; Photographic Prints; Restaurants; Suits; Turkey
- A man with a mustache, wearing a double breasted suit. Ottoman writing on the back. 20.5 x 14.0 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Individual Portrait; Men; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits; Turkey
- Seven men, five with round eye glasses and one wearing a bow tie. Studio Husnu Kazim, Usak, Turkey. 22.5 x 24.1 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Bow Tie; Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Usak, Turkey
- A small family group, female with a head cover, holds a small child in her lap. 19.9 x 14.2 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Children; Family Portraits; Furnishings; Head Covers; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey
- A Zeybek, in traditional clothing, wearing a Fez. 24.1 x 15.5 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Fez; Individual Portrait; Mustaches; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Zeybek
- A group of highschool boys and their female teacher. 18.0 x 24.3 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Boys; Education; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Schools; Turkey; Women
- A small family group, two small children seated in the middle. Foto Sener. 21.0 x 15.7 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Children; Family Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits; Turkey; Women
- An older woman wearing a head cover. 23.2 x 17.4 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Head Covers; Individual Portrait; Photographic Prints; Turkey; Women
- A girls school, with students and teachers. Foto Palas, Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey. "Galatasaray Lisesi Karsisinda, No 100". 21.7 x 26.5 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Education; Girls; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
- A woman and a young girl seated on a ferry. 21.2 x 15.8 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Children; Family; Ferry; Girls; Photographic Prints; Turkey
- A man with round glasses and pocket square. Foto Rekor Universite, Istanbul, Turkey. 29.7 x 18.8 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Foto Rekor, Istanbul, Turkey; Individual Portrait; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
- Two photos of seated children, "Karolesh and Salaha". Ankara, Turkey. Turkish writing on the front. 26.7 x 19.5 cm, 14 May 1937 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Ankara, Turkey; Children; Furnishings; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkish Writing
- Older veiled woman. 24.7 x 19.3 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
- A woman on a ferry on the Bosphorus, with Kizkulesi (Maiden's Tower) in the background. 24.0 x 17.9 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Bosphorous; Ferry; Individual Portrait; Istanbul, Turkey; Maiden's Tower; Photographic Prints; Women
- A young couple, woman has updo. 25.7 x 20.0 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Couple; Jewelry; Makeup; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits; Turkey
- A wedding ceremony, Bayazit Marmara Sinemasi. Turkish writing on the front. 21.3 x 26.2 cm, 8 October 1944 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Children; Group Portraits; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Photographic Prints; Turkish Writing; Wedding Ceremony
- School girls in uniforms on the stairs of the building. 17.6 x 25.0 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Education; Girls; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Turkey; Uniforms
- A young short-haired girl on a chair. 30.0 x 23.4 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Children; Furnishings; Handtinting; Individual Portrait; Jewelry; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey
- A small family group, man, woman and small child seated on a wicker chair with checkered floors. Foto Refik, Balikesir, Turkey. Turkish writing on the front. 29.2 x 18.4 cm, 29 January 1939 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Balikesir, Turkey; Family Portraits; Furnishings; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkish Writing
- A family group, one seated female, one seated male, two standing males in suits. Theodore Servanis, Cadi-Meuy, Constantinople. 31.2 x 24.9 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Constantinople; Family Portraits; Furnishings; Istanbul, Turkey; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
- Two standing women and one girl standing on a chair with checkered dress. 23.8 x 17.9 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Children; Furnishings; Photographic Prints; Turkey; Women
- A couple, female wears a striped dress and male in suit. Turkish writing on the front. 17.4 x 24.7 cm, 9 May 1938 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Couple; Jewelry; Makeup; Photographic Prints; Suits; Turkey; Turkish Writing
- Two women looking off camera. Foto Rekor Universite, Istanbul, Turkey. 21.3 x 24.0 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Foto Rekor, Istanbul, Turkey; Istanbul, Turkey; Makeup; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
- School boys of varied ages in suits. J. Claude Popin (signature). 26.2 x 32.5 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Boys; Education; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Schools; Suits; Turkey
- Two seated covered females, one seated male in light suit, one standing male with bow tie and one standing youth. Ottoman writing on the front. 26.1 x 21.3 cm, 1907 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Family Portraits; Furnishings; Head Covers; Ottoman Writing; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey
- Three men on a boat, pulling another boat. 17.5 x 22.9 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Boats; Men; Photographic Prints; Seas; Turkey
- Children in front, women in second row, and men standing third row. Turkish writing on the front. 23.2 x 27.8 cm, 18 April 1932 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Children; Countryside; Family Portraits; Group Portraits; Handtinting; Photographic Prints; Turkey
- A man with round glasses, pocket square and badge on his jacket. 29.3 x 19.5 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Individual Portrait; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits; Turkey
- A class of school girls of varied ages in dresses and holding diplomas. 20.0 x 25.7 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Architecture; Education; Girls; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Schools; Turkey; Women
- Two females embracing, younger girl in white dress, older woman in black dress. 23.7 x 15.5 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Family; Girls; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Women
- Smiling, older woman. Studio Atlantis. 23.7 x 17.9 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Individual Portrait; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Women
- Three females sitting on stairs in front of the Municipality. 26.7 x 21.8 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Children; Family; Photographic Prints; Turkey; Women
- Man, seated profile, with round glasses, mustache and pocket square. 29.6 x 19.6 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
- A young couple, man is in military uniform. Turkish writing on the front. 22.7 x 17.1 cm, 3 February 1949 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Couple; Military; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Turkish Writing; Uniforms
- A young couple, man in military uniform and woman in a light dress with ruffles and a headband. Foto Sumer. 32.0 x 22.0 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Couple; Makeup; Military; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Uniforms
- Young men with long hair seated around a table, looking at one man writing. Man in the middle has glasses. Ugur Gunyuz, Cumhuriyet, Istanbul. 14.6 x 24.0 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Gatherings; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- A male with a fez and a mustache in traditional dress. Blue stamp in Ottoman writing on back. 23.5 x 18.5 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Fez; Individual Portrait; Men; Mustaches; Ottoman Clothing; Ottoman Writing; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Traditional Dress; Turkey
- Seated couple, man in suit and round sunglasses seated in front of a table with newspaper and fruit. Turkish writing on the back. 32.7 x 26.3 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Couple; Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Furnishings; Newspapers; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Turkish Writing
- A group of men in suits. Foto Rekor, Ankara. Turkish writing on the back. 27.4 x 33.5 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Ankara, Turkey; Foto Rekor, Ankara, Turkey; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Suits; Turkish Writing
- A group of men with Turkish flags on a table and a Turkish flag hanging on the wall in the background. Foto Hilal, Bakirkoy, Istanbul. Turkish writing on the back, 15/10/1961 on the day of general elections and signatures. 26.2 x 32.2 cm, 15 October 1961 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Elections; Flags; Group Portraits; Istanbul, Turkey; Men; Photographic Prints; Political Life; Studio Photography; Turkish Writing
- Man with slicked back hair, a bow tie and a pocket square. Ottoman writing on the back. 28.9 x 19.9 cm, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Bow Tie; Individual Portrait; Men; Ottoman Writing; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey
- Bride in a white ruffled hat and a string of pearls, surrounded by family members. Saraef, Sisli, Istanbul. Armenian writing on the front. 19.5 x 25.5 cm, 26 September 1948 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Armenian Writing; Brides; Family Portraits; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Wedding Portraits; Wedding Veil
- Young seated female with black knee high boots and a black skirt. On reverse, "Bolu, 10, 10, 1972". Foto Muzaffer. 13.3 x 8.3 cm, 10 October 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Bolu, Turkey; Boots; Individual Portrait; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
- A young boy with a bow tie and belt on a pedestal. Text in blue ink on reverse. 13.5 x 8.5 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Bow Tie; Children; Furnishings; Individual Portrait; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey
- A female in a dark dress with dark lipstick, male in a dark suit with a short mustache. Foto Sabah. Reverse has writing in green ink. 8.5 x 11.6 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Couple; Foto Sabah; Istanbul, Turkey; Jewelry; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- Two young girls one in light dress with bow on her head, older female in dark dress with buttons. Studio Kenan. 13.4 x 8.5 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Children; Family; Foto Kenan; Girls; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey
- Two young boys in sailor suits. 13.8 x 8.4 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Boys; Children; Family; Maritime Outfit; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey
- Young girls in uniforms in a classroom, girls in back are giving bunny ears. Istanbul, Turkey. 9.0 x 14.0 cm, October 1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Education; Girls; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Uniforms
- Young girls in white P.E. uniforms walking in rows at a stadium. Writing on reverse in pencil "19 May Commemoration of Atatürk, Youth and Sports Day Celebrations". 9.0 x 14.0 cm (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Ataturk; Education; Girls; Photographic Prints; Sports; Turkey; Turkish Writing
- Young boy and older male is seated in a western suit with tie and pocket square. 19 December 1952, Iskenderun, Turkey. 13.5 x 8.7 cm (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Boys; Family Portraits; Iskenderun, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits; Turkish Writing
- Older male in Western suit is holding a young boy in a white outfit. 13.5 x 8.7 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Boys; Family Portraits; Newspapers; Photographic Prints; Suits; Turkey
- Family group, two young children sitting on a bench in front of a couple. 14.3 x 7.6 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Children; Family Portraits; Furnishings; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey
- A bride and groom are standing. Foto Moda. Turkish writing on the back. 13.5 x 8.3 cm, 10 December 1949 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Couple; Flowers; Foto Moda; Jewelry; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Turkish Writing; Wedding Portraits
- A young female with a hat and her hands in her coat pockets. Foto Moda. Turkish writing on the reverse. 13.5 x 8.5 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Coats; Foto Moda; Girls; Hats; Individual Portrait; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Turkish Writing
- A young couple, woman has arms crossed. 13.5 x 8.7 cm, 18 October 1929 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Couple; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits; Turkey; Turkish Writing
- A female in a dark flowery dress with a dark purse and white gloves held in her right hand. Turkish wiriting on the back. 13.7 x 8.5 cm, 30 June 1941 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Fashion Accessories; Gloves; Individual Portrait; Jewelry; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkey; Turkish Writing; Women
- A female in a white apron and dark dress in front of a window with lace curtains. 11.9 x 9.0 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Individual Portrait; Jewelry; Photographic Prints; Women
- A young couple, female is wearing a dark coat, with a hat and blusher. Foto Kenan, Uskudar, Turkey. 8.8 x 13.4 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Coats; Couple; Foto Kenan; Hats; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- A male, holding baby in white outfit, two younger females in belted dresses. 14.0 x 9.0 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Children; Family Portraits; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
- Two females in a park, older woman is in a dark coat with a white head scarf. 14.1 x 8.9 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Family; Family Portraits; Head Covers; Parks; Photographic Prints; Women
- A group of twelve males in suits. One is wearing a military uniform. 8.5 x 13.6 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Group Portraits; Men; Military; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; Soldiers; Suits; Uniforms
- A woman with crossed arms standing in a corner. 13.6 x 8.5 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Individual Portrait; Photographic Prints; Women
- A family walking in winter coats outside. 8.7 x 13.8 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Coats; Family; Hats; Parks; Photographic Prints
- A group of men, women and children inside a home. Older man in the middle with a light suit, young female in the front with a light flowered dress on. 8.5 x 13.7 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Ceremony; Children; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Women
- A young female sitting on a garden wall in front of some wooden houses. Pendik, Istanbul, Turkey. 13.8 x 8.9 cm, 28 December 1954 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Architecture; Gardens; Individual Portrait; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Women
- A male wearing round, dark glasses and a robe with a sash over his shoulder. Studio Sabah, Istanbul, Turkey. 13.5 x 8.8 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Eye Glasses & Sunglasses; Foto Sabah; Individual Portrait; Law; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkish Writing
- A female seated on a sofa wearing a dark dress with a light colar. Sofa has geometric patterns on the seat. 12.8 x 8.4 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Furnishings; Individual Portrait; Photographic Prints; Women
- A male wearing a Western suit, standing in front of a river with houses in the background. Kucukcekmece, Istanbul, Turkey. 13.6 x 8.5 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Architecture; Individual Portrait; Istanbul, Turkey; Lake Kucukcekmece, Turkey; Men; Photographic Prints
- Four women in a row boat. 9.0 x14.2 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Bathing Suits; Boats; Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Women
- A group of children in front of house with a sewing machine on a table. 8.9 x 13.9 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Architecture; Children; Education; Photographic Prints; Sewing
- A couple seated with a child on a blanket in a garden. Ottoman and French writing on the back. 13.9 x 8.8 cm, 18 July 1931 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Family; Family Portraits; French Writing; Gardens; Hats; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints
- A group of males gathered around a table with bunk beds in the rooms. 8.9 x 13.8 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Boys; Education; Furnishings; Performance Play; Photographic Prints
- A covered female, leaning on a pedestal with a book in her hand. Izmir, Turkey. 13.5 x 8.4 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Books; Furnishings; Individual Portrait; Izmir, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
- A family group in the country side, with three children. 9.0 x 14.0 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Children; Gardens; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Women
- A female in a dark top and dark skirt. Foto Suat. Turkish writing on the back. 13.3 x 8.2 cm, 15 June 1944 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Individual Portrait; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Turkish Writing; Women
- A group males in front of a doorway, two in miltary uniform and hats. Paintings in the room. Ottoman and Turkish writing on the back. 8.8 x 13.5 cm, 15 August 1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Group Portraits; Men; Military; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; Turkish Writing; Uniforms
- A male standing in front of curtains, wearing a dark suit with a white pocket square. Armenian writing on the back. 13.8 x 8.8 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Armenian Writing; Individual Portrait; Men; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
- Girls sitting on grass and sand in front of a wooden fence. 8.4 x 13.4 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Coats; Girls; Group Portraits; Hats; Photographic Prints
- A young couple seated in a park holding a baby wearing a light outfit. Female has head covered. 8.9 x 14.0 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Children; Couple; Family Portraits; Head Covers; Parks; Photographic Prints